Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: [A]. Economic Theory and its History, (8 Boxes: Boxes 1-3; 28-32)
  - 79 [1905 or 1907?]; hol. 13 p.; advanced economics seminar; economic man. (Box 28, Folder A603)
  - 80 [before 1913]; hol. 4 p.; lecture notes; Bentham - life and influence, reforms. (Box 28, Folder A521)
  - 81 [before 1913]; hol. 2 p.; J.S. Mill, Senior, McCulloch, Torrens. (Box 28, Folder A522)
  - 82 [before 1913]; hol. 10 p.; lecture notes; Physiocrats, class plans. (Box 28, Folder A523)
  - 83 [before 1313?]; hol. 3 p.; hedonism, marginal utility. (Box 28, Folder A723)
  - 84. [before 1913]; hol. 6 p.; lecture notes; economic psychology. (Box 28, Folder A525)
  - 85 [before 1913]; hol. 1 p.; contractual relations. (Box 28, Folder A471)
  - 86 [before 1913]; hol. 4 p.; Advanced Economics Seminar; Veblen’s "Preconceptions", J.S. Mill, Scoffer, Cairnes, J.N. Keynes, Marshall, Malthus, Utilitarians. (Box 28, Folder A552)
  - 87. [before 1913]; hol. 1 p.; Utilitarianism and pecuniary activity. (Box 28, Folder A559)
  - 88. [about 1916]; hol. 10 p.; Ricardo - on rent, aim, method, assumptions. (Box 28, Folder A462)
  - 89. [after 1922]; hol. 3 p.; Tp. Veblen, Ashley, Sombart, Ricardo, Commons, socialists, Fourier, St. Simon, .Marx, S. & B. Webb, Historical School (Box 28, Folder A480)
  - 90. [before 1925?]; hol. 1 p.; Ricardian economics, human nature uniformity. (Box 28, Folder A48)
  - 91. 193?, March25 typed ms l p.; suggestions for seminar by Dirks. (Box 28, Folder A513)
  - 92. [1938 or 1939], typed & hol. 1 p.; EC; list of students. (Box 28, Folder A611)
  - 93 typed; 2 p.; quotes by J. Abercrombie: property rights. (Box 28, Folder A86)
  - 94 typed 8 p.; quotes by Lord Acton: Revolution of 1689 and in America, party origins, Whigs in 1768. (Box 28, Folder A73)
  - 95 typed 27 p.; quotes by A. Allyson; economics, class war, inventors, distribution, Sismondi, history, land, trade unions, factory work, conservatism, crises, middle class. (Box 28, Folder A87)
  - 96. typed 21 p.; quotes by B.M. Anderson; value theory. (Box 28, Folder A88)
  - 97. typed 7 p.; quotes by J. Anderson; rent, land distribution. (Box 28, Folder A94)
  - 98. typed, 3 p.; quotes by T. Arnold; Society for Diffusion of Knowledge, liberalism and economics. (Box 28, Folder A89)
  - 99. typed & hol. Up.; quotes by W. Ashley; freedom of contract, logic and sciences, historical method, economics and businessman, capital and industrial revolution, 18th century land system, popularity of economics, R. Jones, English economics professorships. (Box 28, Folder A90)
  - 100. typed 2 p.; life of A. Auspit3 (Schumpeter). (Box 28, Folder A91)
  - 101. typed 4 p.; quotes by J. Austin; economics. (Box 28, Folder A92)
  - 102. typed 6 p.; quotes by C. Ayres; economics and institutions. (Box 28, Folder A93)
  - 103. typed Up.; life of C. Babbage (Bonar); quotes: origin of man, mathematics chair, London Statistical Society, Society for the Promotion of Analysis. (Box 28, Folder A95)
  - 104. typed 21 p.; quotes by W. Baghot: economics, Smith, Ricardo, Malthus; abstract: Economic Studies. (Box 28, Folder A96)
  - 105 hol. & typed 25 p.; quotes by S. Bailey: Malthus, popularizing economics, value, economics as mental philosophy, Mill and McCulloch on time and value (wine), capital cost - Mill and Torrens; abstract: Critical Dissertation on Value. (Box 28, Folder A97)
  - 106. typed 8 p.; quotes by A. Bain: Moleswort, propaganda, Roebuck, Society for the diffusion of Useful Knowledge, economics and Universities, J. Mill on McCulloch, Westminster Review (Box 28, Folder A98)
  - 107. typed 2 p.; quotes by E. Baines: free trade movement, 11 hour day. (Box 28, Folder A99)
  - 108. typed 12 p.; quotes by T. Banfieid: rent, industry and economics, social capital, wages and profits, population, historical and descriptive economics, foreign influence on English economics, value theory, applicability of economics. (Box 28, Folder A100)
  - 109. hol. 1 p.; J. Barton bibliography. (Box 28, Folder A571)
  - 110. hol. 52 p.; abstract of Bastait: Harmonies Economiques; life. (Box 28, Folder A101)
  - 111. hol. 1 p.; work of L. Bell. (Box 28, Folder A102)
  - 112. typed and hol. 77 p.; quotes by J. Bentham: Blackstone, value, Lind, Wilson, Romilly, felicific calculus, French Declaration of Rights, labor, diminishing utility, science and art, rights/and calculation, money, savage and civilized man, boredom, education, emotion, transplanting laws, human perfectibility, habits, rationality, pleasure and happiness, Owen, 3rou£ham, Hume, Hunt, O’Connell, Ricardo, Burdett, Whigs and reform, Cobbett, utilitarianism, Carlisle, J. Mill, Peel, judiciary, Wellington, S. Smith and penal code, French 1830 Revolution, English constitution, poetry, social science; life. (Box 28, Folder A572)
  - 1. typed 1 p.; quote by Miss Berry: Malthus. (Box 29, Folder A103)
  - 2. hol. 1 p.; quote by Blackwood: economics and labor. (Box 29, Folder A573)
  - 3. typed 2 p.; quotes by Blanqui: industrial revolution. (Box 29, Folder A104)
  - 4. hol. ,3: typed 48 p.; quotes on E. Bohm Bawerk by Bonar, Schumpeter, Philippovich; abstract: Positive Theory of Capital. (Box 29, Folder A105)
  - 5 typed & hol. 9 p.; quote by J. Bonar: hedonism, Malthus and Ricardo; references on: Ricardo’s Ingot Plan, proportions, utilitarianism (see A149). (Box 29, Folder A112)
  - 6. typed, l p.; quote by G. Booth: import embargo and corn. (Box 29, Folder A296)
  - 7 typed 1 p.; quote by C. Bosanquet: Ricardo pamphlet. (Box 29, Folder A106)
  - 8. typed 9 p.; quotes by J. Bowring: Bentham (life), Dumont, Eldon, Wooler, Catechism, R. Smith, Colquhoun, self. (Box 29, Folder A575)
  - 9. typed 1 p.; life of C. Bray. (Box 29, Folder A113)
  - 10. typed 14 p.; quotes by J. Bray: exploitation, economic psychology, economics, first principles, social organization, tax incidence. (Box 29, Folder A114)
  - 11 typed 1 p.; quotes by J. Bright: aristocrats in parliament. (Box 29, Folder A564)
  - 12. hol 1 p; quote by E. Brit[?]: cabinet. (Box 29, Folder A115)
  - 13 typed 1 p; quotes by J. Broadhurst: landlords, Ricardo and Malthus, manufacture and agriculture, education, wages, Torrens and cost of production theory; references to Political Economy. (Box 29, Folder A116)
  - 14 typed & hol. 4 p.; reference on Brougham:- Ricardo's method; quotes: Wellington, Baring, Whigs and reform. (Box 29, Folder A107)
  - 15. typed 6 p.; quotes by G. Browning: income distribution, French economics, overpopulation; reference: Domestic and Financial Condition of Great Britain. (Box 29, Folder A108)
  - 16. typed 6 p.; quotes by H. Buckle: economics, J.S. Mill, life (Ruth) (Box 29, Folder A109)
  - 17. typed 38 p.; quotes by Burton: competition, production, supply and demand, value, taxation, poor and rich, property, strikes, factory legislation, emigration, communism, insurance, free trade, motive, education, wages, labor, capital, population; contents of and authors quoted in Political Economy; WCM notes. (Box 29, Folder A117)
  - 18. typed 3 p.; quote by W. Bush: value and causality. (Box 29, Folder All0)
  - 19. typed 6 p.; quotes by I. Butt: professorship, marginal productivity; life. (Box 29, Folder Alll)
  - 20. hol. & typed 15 p.; quotes by J. Cairnes: teaching economics, laissez-faire, public and economics, cooperation, economics as science; WCM notes. (Box 29, Folder All8)
  - 21. typed 8 p.; quotes by 7;. Camp; Ricardian rent theory. (Box 29, Folder A459)
  - 22.typed 1 p.; quote by Lord Campbell: criminal law reform. (Box 29, Folder A84)
  - 23.hol. & typed 4 p.; quote by E. Cannan: laissez-faire; abstract: History of Theories. (Box 29, Folder A120)
  - 24. 7 p.; abstract of R. Cantillian: Essai sur la nature du commerce (see Petty) (Box 29, Folder A208)
  - 25. typed 18 p.; quotes by E. Carlyle: Cobbett. (Box 29, Folder A625)
  - 26. retyped 9 p.; quotes by Carlyle: English wealth, egoism, hedonism, pecuniary habits, reforms, aristocracy, idleness. (Box 29, Folder A119)
  - 27. typed 1 p.; quote by R. Carmichael: mathematics in economics. (Box 29, Folder A140)
  - 28. hol. 14 p.; abstracts of T.'T. Carver's Distribution of Wealth, Place of Abstinence in the Theory of Interest, Concept of an economic quantity. (Box 29, Folder Al2l)
  - 29. hol. 1 p.; life of G. Cassel. (Box 29, Folder A454)
  - 30. typed 1 p.; quote by E. Cayle: commercial economics. (Box 29, Folder A252)
  - 31. typed 2 p.; quote by J. Cozenove; from Elementary Treatise; contents list of Thoughts on a few subjects in Political Economy. (Box 29, Folder A122)
  - 32. typed 20 p.; quote by E. Chadwick: labor as capital, cost analysis, from introduction to Health of Nations; life. (Box 29, Folder A123)
  - 33. hol. & typed 9 p.; quote by T. Chalmers: Physiocrats; abstract: theory of maintenance; life. (Box 29, Folder A124)
  - 34. typed 12 p.; quotes by Chapman: economics, utility, psychology, consumers’ and producers’ surplus, economics and experience. (Box 29, Folder A125)
  - 35 hol. 1 p.; reference to 11, Charlesworth: Trade Routes and Commerce of the Roman Empire.. (Box 29, Folder A128)
  - 36 hol. 1 p.; reference to J. Clapham: "Of Empty Economic Boxes." (Box 29, Folder A123)
  - 37 hol. 3 p.; abstract of J.B. Clark: Philosophy of health. (Box 29, Folder A127)
  - 38 typed 25 p.; quotes by J.M. Clark: Veblen, exchange rates and ratios, value, psychology (Jevons and Bohn Bawerk), Pigou, English economic tradition, individualism, government costs, socialism and employment, from "Changing Basis of Economic Responsibility". (Box 29, Folder A139)
  - 39. typed 26 p.; quotes by Cobden: wages, farmers, free trade, laissez-fairre, economics, property rights, agriculture, consistency, parliament, Peel, parties, manufacturers, classes, A. Smith. (Box 29, Folder A129)
  - 40. typed l p. quote by G. Coe: social psychology. (Box 29, Folder A130)
  - 41. typed 1 p.; life and works of P. Colquhou. (Box 29, Folder A131)
  - 42. hol. & typed; quotes, J. Colons: Natural law, capitalism origins, Law of Equity, goodwill and value, transactions and law;, business revolution, from "Political Economy and Business Economy"; abstract: Legal Foundations of Capitalism. (Box 29, Folder A132)
  - 43. hol. 15 p.; abstract of Condillac: theory of value. (Box 29, Folder A133)
  - 44. typed 17 p.; quotes by C. Cooley: valuation. (Box 29, Folder A134)
  - 45. typed 2 p.; quotes by T. Corbet: economics and policy. (Box 29, Folder A135)
  - 46. typed 1 p.; quote by M. Copeland: price and welfare. (Box 29, Folder A626)
  - 47. typed 4 p.; quotes by T. Cotterill: theory of value. (Box 29, Folder A136)
  - 48. typed 5 p.; quotes by Cournot: wealth. (Box 29, Folder A137)
  - 49. typed 7 p.; quotes by J. Craig: rent, wages, profits, taxes on wages, land and capital, use and exchange value. (Box 29, Folder A138)
  - 50. hol. 1 p.; abstract of W. Cunningham: concept of welfare. (Box 29, Folder A141)
  - 51. hol. 1 p.; reference to A. Cutler: "Ebb of Institutional Economics". (Box 29, Folder A627)
  - 52. hol. 2 p.; abstract of B. Davanzati: Lezione delle Monete. (Box 29, Folder A142)
  - 53. typed &. hol.; 23p.; quotes by H. Davenport: Jevons, social productivity, interest rates and banking, cost, exhausted farms; abstract: "Capitalization and Market Value". (Box 29, Folder A143)
  - 54. typed 1.; quote by J. Davis: rents. (Box 29, Folder A144)
  - 55. typed 7 p.; quotes by T7. Dawson: wages and labor, 1814 economic policy, interest rate and profit and wages; life; WCM notes. (Box 29, Folder A145)
  - 56. hol. 1 p.; quote by C. Day: industrial leadership. (Box 29, Folder A565)
  - 57 typed 9 p.; quotes by de Quincey: self, Ricardo, Malthus, use value, market value. (Box 29, Folder A146)
  - 58. hol. 1 p.; life of de Tracy. (Box 29, Folder A566)
  - 59. hol. 3: typed 15 p.; quotes by J. Dewey from: "Measure for the Worth of any Given Mode of Social Life"; "Judgments of Practice"; on: social psychology; abstract: Reflex Arc Concept in Psychology". (Box 29, Folder A147)
  - 60. typed 12 p.; quotes by Dibblee: demand manipulation, economic man; value and wealth, businessman and innovators. (Box 29, Folder A148)
  - 61. hol. 1 p.; quote by A. Dicey: Benthanism. (Box 29, Folder A567)
  - 62. hol. 1 p.; reference to K. Diehl: utilitarianism (see Bonar). (Box 29, Folder A149)
  - 63. hol. 44p.; abstract of H. Dietzel: Theoretische Sozial ökononië. (Box 29, Folder A150)
  - 64. hol. 1 p.; quote by C. Doten: value theory. (Box 29, Folder A151)
  - 65. typed 1 p.; quote by G. Douglas: economists’ ignorance of land management. (Box 29, Folder A152)
  - 66.hol. 4 p.,* abstract of E. Downy: "Futility of Marginal Utility". (Box 29, Folder A153)
  - 67. typed 6 p.; quote by H. Drummond: landlords and capitalists, corn laws and classes; life. (Box 29, Folder A154)
  - 68. typed 1 p.; quote by Dumont: Bentham. (Box 29, Folder A568)
  - 69. typed 4 p.; quote by K. Dunlap: instinct psychology. (Box 29, Folder A155)
  - 70. hol. 13 p.; life of Dupont de Nemours; abstract: De l'origine et de progrèsd'une Science Nouvelle. (Box 29, Folder A156)
  - 71. typed & hol. 16 p.; quotes by F.Y. Edgeworth: Marshall and general equilibrilium, applied economics, measurement of utility, Bohm Bawrerk and utility, money and equilibrium. (Box 29, Folder A157)
  - 72. typed 23 p.; quotes by T. Edmunds; taxes on wages, agricultural improvements, private property, population, competition, luxury, psychology, money economy, eugenics, labor; WCM notes. (Box 29, Folder A158)
  - 73. typed 2 p.; quotes by ft. Ellis from Outlines of Social Economy; life. (Box 29, Folder A159)
  - 74. typed 12 p.; quotes by H. Faulkner: Chartism. (Box 29, Folder A160)
  - 75. typed 2 p.; life of H. Fawcett (Price). (Box 29, Folder A161)
  - 76. hol. 4 p.; quote by Fetter: distribution; abstract: Principles of Economics. (Box 29, Folder A162)
  - 77. hol., typed, carbon 20 p.; quotes by I. Fisher: psychic income, capital and valuation (Veblen), social psychology and valuation (Commons), utility measurement, distribution (Davenport) (Box 29, Folder Al64)
  - 78. typed 6 p.; quotes by A. Flux: Hobson (Economics of Distribution), Pantaleoni (Pure Economics). (Box 29, Folder A166)
  - 79. hol 1 p.; reference to E. Fortsone [?]: Selections from the Speeches and Writings of the Late Lord King; and Lord King's Thoughts on the Restoration of Payments in Specie. (Box 29, Folder A163)
  - 80. typed 6 p.; quotes by H. Foxwell: English economics, 1848-1887. (Box 29, Folder A165)
  - 81. typed 3 p.; quotes by S. Gale: public credit. hol. 6 p.; abstract of Galiani: Della Moneta (see A142) (Box 29, Folder A569)
  - 82. hol. 1 p.; quote by P. Gaskell; economics and reality. (Box 29, Folder A167)
  - 1. typed 3 p.; quote by J. Goddard: Mechanics Institute (Box 30, Folder A168)
  - 2typed 14 p.; quotes, J. Graham: tax on fund holder, corn price effects, capitalists and landlords (corn laws), private property; life and works (Parker) (Box 30, Folder A169)
  - 3. typed 20 p.; quotes by J. Gray: competition, occupations, conspicuous waste, productive and unproductive classes, statistics, value theory, rent and interest, reforms, exchange scheme; life. (Box 30, Folder A170)
  - 4. typed 4 p.; quotes by W. Greg: labor, unions, wage theory. (Box 30, Folder A171)
  - 5. hol. 1 p.; reference to T. Gregory: "Economics of Employment in England 1660-1713". (Box 30, Folder A332)
  - typed 3 p.; quotes by [Lord?] Grey: Canning and Whigs, England after Peterloo (Box 30, Folder A575)
  - typed 19p.; quotes by Mrs. Grote: G. Grote’s life and work, C. Austin, London University, Mill and Oxford, Philosophical Radicals, Compte. (Box 30, Folder A570)
  - typed 2 p.; quote by A. T. Hadley: competition. (Box 30, Folder A172)
  - typed 2 p.; quotes by R. Hale: distribution, classical economics and policy. (Box 30, Folder A630)
  - (l) typed and hol. 122 p.; quotes by Halevy: Condorcet, Godwin, Malthus, A. Smith, J. Mill, J.S. Mill, psychology, population, saving, interpersonal comparisons, social and individual interests, Ricardo and irrationality, Ricardo, Bentham, value, free trade, Moral Arithmetic (Smith), technological unemployment (Ricardo), McCulloch. (2) Bentham, property, equality of rights, naturalism in economics, Godwin and Paley, A. Smith and democracy, marginal utility, psychology, Labor irksomeness, perfectibility, public and utility, chrestomathic schools, Newton. (Box 30, Folder A68)
  - 12. typed 12 p.; quotes by R. Hamilton: wages, income distribution, diminishing utility and income equality, emulation; life; WCM note on statistics/historical and genetic economics (Box 30, Folder A173)
  - 13. typed 11 p.; quotes by W. Hamilton: mechanistic and organic economics, political and economic democracy, class economics and price system. (Box 30, Folder A174)
  - 14. typed 10 p.; quotes by J. and B. Hamilton: English property and classes, Philosophical Radicals and aristocracy, public and economics. (Box 30, Folder A175)
  - 15. typed 6 p.; quotes by L. Haney from: "Process of Value Causation", "Opportunity Cost". (Box 30, Folder A176)
  - 16 hol. 1 p.; reference to W. Harris: History of the Radical Party in Parliament, W. Taylor. (Box 30, Folder A177)
  - 17. hol. 13 p.; (1/24/12); abstract and quotes from D. Hartley: Observations on Man; life. (Box 30, Folder A455)
  - 18. hol. 1 p.; reference to Von Hayek: "Economics and Knowledge", "Counter Revolution in Science", "Scientism and the Study of Society". (Box 30, Folder A605)
  - 19. typed 1 p.; quotes by A. Helps: duties of employers. (Box 30, Folder A179)
  - 20. typed 1 p.; quote by H. Higgs: Jevons and own Principles. (Box 30, Folder A251)
  - 21. typed 1 p.; quote by W. Hitchcock: man and his future. (Box 30, Folder A178)
  - 22. typed 18 p.; quotes by J. Hobhouse: Roseberry, Ricardo, self, Westminster election 1818 Catholic Bill, J. Graham, Factory Bill 1825 Reform Bill, J. Hume. (Box 30, Folder A574)
  - 23. hol. &-. typed 35 p.; quotes "by J. Hobson: human costs, capital, saving, distribution, classical and psychological economic theory, marginal theory; life; abstract: Evolution of Modern Capitalism. (Box 30, Folder A180)
  - 24. typed 8 p.; quotes by T. Hodgskin: Ricardo and wages, capital unproductiveness, distribution theory, reason, labor value theory. (Box 30, Folder A181)
  - 25. retyped 4 p.; quotes by T. Hodgskin: C. Bray, economic laws; life. (Box 30, Folder A182)
  - 26 typed 6 p.; quotes by Lord Holland: George II, George III, bran (Addington), cabinet system, Peace of Amiens, Stanhope. (Box 30, Folder A80)
  - 27. typed & hol. 21 p.; quotes by J. Hollander: Ricardo, distribution, method, economics 1776-1809 reference: Arias Smith, 1776-1926. (Box 30, Folder A183)
  - 28. typed 1 p.; abstract of J. Hopkins: Notions on Political Economy. (Box 30, Folder A184)
  - 29. typed 8 p.; quotes by T. Hopkins: rent and wage theory, Ricardo and Malthus, history, history and experiment in economics. (Box 30, Folder A185)
  - 30. typed 6 p.; quote by Homer: Quesney, Bullion Report, WN, Malthus, D. Stewart's lectures. (Box 30, Folder A186)
  - 31 typed 1 p.; quote, by A. Humphrey: economists and workers candidate 1870. (Box 30, Folder A187)
  - 32. typed 2 p.; quote by J. Ingram: public and economics 1820-60. (Box 30, Folder A188)
  - 33. hol. 5 p.; (1/28/12); quote and abstract from Janet and Seailles: association of ideas. (Box 30, Folder A85)
  - 34. hol. 37p.y abstract of R. Jennings: Natural Elements of Political Economy. (Box 30, Folder A189)
  - 35. hol. & typed 64 p.; quotes by W.S. Jevons: own life and work, political views, from "Future of Political Economy"; life; abstract: Theory. (Box 30, Folder A190)
  - 36. hol. 2 p.; quotes by A. Johnson: Fisher’s Elementary Economics, Bonn Bawerk’s Kapital u. Kapitalzius. (Box 30, Folder A191)
  - 37. typed 4 p.; quotes by W. Johnston: conservatism, economics and selfishness, progress; WCM note. (Box 30, Folder A192)
  - 38. typed 3 p.; quote by T. Joplin: currency management plan; WCM note on statistics. (Box 30, Folder A193)
  - 39. typed & hol. 25 p.; quotes by R. Jones: rent; life; Abstract: Theory of Farmers' Rent. (Box 30, Folder A194)
  - 40. hol. 1 p.; quote by C. Judd: "Evaluation and consciousness." (Box 30, Folder A195)
  - 41. hol. & typed 4 p.; quotes by J. M. Keynes: Hobson, Baghot as psychologist; reference to "William Stanley Jevons" and "Discussion of Mr. Keynes’ Paper" Lord King; see A163 (Box 30, Folder A196)
  - 42. typed 15 p.; quotes by S. Laing: competition and monopoly, National Distress, mechanistic economics; life. (Box 30, Folder A197)
  - 43. typed 5 p.; quotes by Yi, Landor: Sheridan and peerage seats, child labor, English revolts 1812 Pitt and Fox. (Box 30, Folder A198)
  - 44. typed l p.; quote by Langston: Manchester and London Statistical Societies, Quetelet (Box 30, Folder A199)
  - 45. hol. 4 p.; abstract of W,. Lauderdale: Inquiry in to the Nature and Origin of Public Wealth; life (Box 30, Folder A200)
  - 46. typed 6 p.; quotes by J. Larson: utility, savage and natural states, economics as science. (Box 30, Folder A201)
  - 47. typed & hol. 67 p.; quotes by C. Leslie: A. Smith (induction, deduction, theology), Ricardo, economics and community and family, motives, a priori method, Baghot and economics limitation, wages and profits, public and private interests, index numbers, consumption, history as science, history and ethics, economics and sociology, taxation and labor, gold and prices, wealth inequalities, town life and acquisitiveness, celibacy, poor, domestic and international, values, medieval and modern economic life; abstract: Essays; life. (Box 30, Folder A202)
  - 48. hol. 27 p.; abstract of Le Trosne: De l'intéret social; life. (Box 30, Folder A203)
  - 49. typed 1 p.; quote by G. Lewis: moral sciences in 1847. (Box 30, Folder A576)
  - 50. typed 3 p.; quote by W. Lippman: Marshall and incentive measurement. (Box 30, Folder A204)
  - 51 hol. 23 p.; abstract of List: Das Nationale System. (Box 30, Folder A205)
  - 51. typed 4 p.; quotes by W. Lloyd: method, marginal utility. (Box 30, Folder A206)
  - 53. typed 30 p.; quotes by M. Longfield: class interest, speculation, distribution, abstraction and supposition, rationality economics and history, economic theory and practice, economic interest, time element, utility and marginal analysis. (Box 30, Folder A207)
  - 54. hol.60 p.; abstract of Loria: Economic Basis of Social Constitution. (Box 30, Folder A209)
  - 55. hol. 1 p.; quote by J. Lowe: England in 1822. (Box 30, Folder A577)
  - 56. hol. 3 p.; quote by T. Macauly: Utilitarians. (Box 30, Folder A579)
  - 57. typed l p.; quote by J. Mackenzie: pleasure and value. (Box 30, Folder A210)
  - 58. hol. 7 p.; abstract of S. Nacvane: --Marginal Utility and Value. (Box 30, Folder A216)
  - 59. typed, 1 p.; quote by MacWickar: completeness of economics. (Box 30, Folder A211)
  - 60. typed 50 p.; quotes by Malthus: method, unproductive labor, population principle beneficence, distribution and prices, wages and profits, rent, psychology, French population, agriculture and manufacturing, bias, labor, cost of production, short run, doctrine of proportions, money, oversimplification in economics, value, landlords, poverty and character, rationality, utilitarianism, checks on population, wealth. (Box 30, Folder A212)
  - 61. hol. & typed 49 p.; quotes by A. Marshall: money, money economy, supply and value, motives, Mill (value), classical economists, Napoleonic Wars and income, industrial revolution, hedonism, reconciliation of schools; abstract (outline): Principles; references in Principles. (Box 30, Folder A213)
  - 62. hol. 2 p.; abstract of K. Marx: rent. (Box 30, Folder A460)
  - 63. typed 1 p.; quote by R. McCrea: Austrians and marginal productivity. (Box 30, Folder A214)